Adam Bohling | Software Engineer

Centennial, CO 80122 | (608) 217-1130 | abohling011@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/adambohling/ https://bohlingportfolio.com/

Summary

I'm a full-stack web developer with a background in sales and management. Since graduating from Springboard's Full Stack Engineering program, I have worked with private companies building websites and improving SEO. I have focused on building and testing applications using React, JS, Redux, Python, and SQL. I have used my problem solving and collaborative skills on challenging projects, and I am motivated to continue my learning as a software developer.

Technical Skills

Languages: CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Python, PHP, and SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: Git, Ajax, jQuery, Flask, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, Express, React, Redux, Jest, Jasmine, SQLAlchemy, and WordPress

Skills: WordPress, Agile Methodologies, Computer Science Fundamentals, Problem Solving, Data Analysis, DOM Manipulation, Web Development, Data Structures, and Event-Driven Programming

Freelance Work

Good Signature - https://goodsignature.com/

-Updated a static WordPress website and added custom PHP-based templates which cuts down on posting times and allows the owner to modify content without coding. Also, added sitemaps, took down all broken links, initiated a 3-click web flow, and removed old or bloated plugins to optimize speed.

Elevated Fitness Website - https://github.com/abohling/Elevated-Fitness && https://elevatedfitsolutions.com/

-Built a company website that allows customizable payment to allocate funds to various accounts. The website uses NodeJS, SQL, and Express on the backend and React and JavaScript on the front-end. Savable accounts, allow the users to make payments using the Strip-API.

Work Experience

Springboard Full Stack Software Engineering Career Track - May 2022 - May 2023

- Frontend Development- Worked with Python, JS, React, and Jquery. Projects included building messaging boards, remaking a Twitter clone, and creating a Jeopardy game
- Backend Development Worked with Express, Flask, SQL, and Postgres to build databases, APIs, data structures, and different algorithms. Projects included making a song library and foreign exchange converter.

Elevated Fitness Solutions, Centennial - Owner - November 2021 - PRESENT

- Utilize a self-designed booking website using the technologies ReactJS, NodeJS, and Express, Strip API.
- Execute day-to-day business operations including bookkeeping, scheduling, training, and customer service.
- Consult with +30 customers weekly by assessing personal needs to create short-term achievable goals.

Anytime Fitness, Denver— *Area Manager* – June 2016 – June 2018

- Oversaw day-to-day operations for multiple locations with an \$80k monthly review.
- Created and defined the organizational structure for the area, including trainers, managers, sales teams, and office personnel.
- Exceeded sale and review targets by 48% for two consecutive years.

Education

Springboard, Remote - Full Stack Software Engineering - March 2021 - April 2022

Madison College, Madison, WI - Associates of Arts - August 2012 - May 2014